SATONO GROUP PRE-G1 CONFERENCE
(里見集團GI壯行會)
It's autumn now. G1 is upon us.
終於來到秋季的GI大賽了
Yes. I will win Kikuka Sho.
是的 我一定會贏下菊花賞的
We will pray for you.
我們也會誠心為妳祝福的
All the best.
妳要好好加油喔
Thank you. I will win G1 for my family.
這是當然 我一定會為里見奪下GI勝利
What a devoted child. Don't let me down now.
真是可靠 我很看好妳喔
See you.
再見了
-I can't wait. -Me too.
-真是令人期待呢 -是啊
As usual, our uncles hold you in high regard.
叔叔他們還是一樣很看好妳呢
Are you ready for Kikuka Sho?
菊花賞準備得如何呢
Yes, I am. Crown, are you competing abroad again?
很順利 皇冠妳又要去海外遠征了對吧
Before that, I have to participate in Tenno Sho this autumn.
在那之前我要先參加秋季的天皇賞
Let's do our best together.
彼此互相加油吧
Yes.
好
Crown lost in Satsuki Sho due to overleaning
皇冠在皐月賞時因斜行輸掉了比賽
and Diamond lost in Satsuki for the same reason too.
光鑽在皐月賞時 也是因為相同原因輸掉
In Derby, she lost because her horseshoes fell off.
德比時則是因為蹄鐵脫落
Who knows what mishap will show up in Kikuka Sho this time?
不知道這次的菊花賞 又會發生什麼事
Even the promising Diamond lost.
連實力頂尖的光鑽也贏不了
Is this the Satono curse?
這也是因為里見的魔咒嗎
I guess no horse girls from the Satono family can win G1.
果然里見的賽馬娘贏不了GI嗎
Crown.
皇冠
But…
可是…
Prove them wrong with results.
結果就是一切
EPISODE 6: DIAMOND
(第6話 鑽石)
Diamond is very motivated.
光鑽她很有衝勁呢
She is fully prepared.
準備得很充分
I'm sure she will ace the 3,000-meter-long sprint
這樣看來這次的菊花賞
in the Kyoto Racecourse this Kikuka Sho.
淀競馬場的3000公尺長距離賽事 也不是問題
It's the final race of the triple crown classic races.
經典三冠的最後一場比賽
She's got it this time.
這一次她絕對會贏的
That's right.
是啊
Satsuki Sho. Derby.
皐月賞 德比
I was physically and mentally prepared for them.
當時的我做足了準備 也做好了心態上的調整
I thought I could win the race
我認為足以打破這種魔咒
and break the curse.
我要贏下比賽 藉此證明這一點
However…
然而…
Divinity appeared from the flank!
居然 神力從外側衝出來了
She left everyone behind.
神力從外側一口氣甩開眾人
No. 8, Satono Diamond, follows closely behind
8號里見光鑽以些微之差緊追其後
but is unable to overtake her.
但還是沒能夠反敗為勝
If neither speed nor strength can dispel this curse,
如果只靠速度… 只靠實力無法打破魔咒的話…
I shall…
那我就要將這個魔咒…
I'll dig in now.
我開動了
And now, today's horoscope.
接著是星座運勢
Let's check out the 11th and the 12th place.
來看看第十一名和最後一名
"HOROSCOPE" Taking the 11th place is Aquarius.
(星座運勢) 第十一名的是水瓶座的你
"11TH AQUARIUS"
(第十一名 水瓶座)
Today is not your day.
今天不管做什麼都會特別不順
Today is not
(不幸顏色 紅色)
"UNLUCKY COLOUR: RED" and stay away from red items.
要小心紅色
Red items…
紅色…
SHICHIMI SPICE
(七味唐辛子)
That's a lot of shichimi in your miso soup. You probably can't drink it anymore…
味噌湯裡加了那麼多七味唐辛子 應該不能喝了吧…
Diamond, are you all right?
光鑽 妳沒事吧
Yes, I'm fine.
嗯 我沒事
Sorry, Kita. I have to go now.
抱歉 小北 我今天要先走了
Okay.
好…
What got into Diamond today?
光鑽她是怎麼了…
And the last place is Pisces.
而最後一名是雙魚座
That's me!
是我啊
FORTUNE TELLER
(有占無患)
Fukukita, please read my fortune.
福來　請幫我占卜
Woo.
嘿嘿嗯
Let me see.
好吧
I see omens.
是凶
Do not head east. It's bad.
不能往東走 是凶
Misfortune surrounds you.
妳的周圍將會發生不祥之事
East, is it?
東邊是嗎
Yes. Never go east. It's bad. Very bad.
是的 絕對不能往東走 此乃大凶
There must be a solution, Fuku.
就沒有什麼辦法嗎 福學姐
Something to ward off the bad luck?
沒有解凶之法嗎
Let me see.
交給我吧
I see hope in the west.
西方有一線生機
No need for that.
不用了
Thank you so much.
謝謝妳們
Don't you want to get rid of your bad luck?
妳不想解凶嗎
Diamond was not herself this morning.
光鑽她早上是怎麼了呢
Diamond?
光鑽
East should be this side.
東方是這邊對吧
Just a small setback…
這點小事…
I just overcame the bad luck Fukukita foretold.
好 克服了待兼福來的占卜
Next!
下一個
Fortune-telling, huh?
占卜…
"COPANO RICKEY" You want to summon bad luck?
(小林歷奇) 妳想知道召喚不幸的方法
Yes. What should I do?
是的 我該怎麼做才好呢
To avoid misfortune, you can rely on feng shui.
這樣啊 要迴避不幸的話 風水是很重要的喔
You can count on me.
交給我吧
Let me check.
我就來幫妳看看喔
Hmm…
這個嘛…
Apparently, you should avoid woody areas.
看來對現在的光鑽來說 樹木繁多的地方不太好
They will bring misfortune to you.
那裡可以召喚不幸吧
Woody areas, you say?
樹木繁多的地方嗎
Thank you.
謝謝妳
Be careful.
妳要小心喔
And good luck!
加油
Feng shui?
風水…
Woody areas. I guess it's around here.
樹木繁多的地方 就是這附近了吧
Let's train hard today.
今天也要來大練特練
Bakushin. Bakushin. Bakushin.
爆進爆進爆進…
Bakushin. Bakushin.
爆進 爆進
Bakushin-shin!
爆進進
Bakushin. Bakushin. Bakushin.
爆進爆進爆進…
Bakushin. Bakushin.
爆進 爆進
Bakushin-shin!
爆進進
Bakushin O!
驀進王
Good. I overcame the bad luck Rickey foretold.
好 歷奇的風水也克服了
Next!
下一個
LIBRARY
(圖書室)
Let's see…
我看看…
"7 URBAN LEGENDS OF TRACEN ACADEMY" At 4:44PM,
(特雷森學園七大不可思議) 在4點44分時
play the piano in the music room
去彈音樂教室的鋼琴的話
"7 URBAN LEGENDS OF TRACEN ACADEMY" and the feet monster will appear.
(特雷森學園七大不可思議) 就會出現"只有腳的妖怪"
All right then.
好
Where did Diamond go?
光鑽她跑去哪裡了
4:43PM
(下午4點43分)
4:44PM
(下午4點44分)
DO NOT PLAY THE PIANO
(請不要彈鋼琴)
"DO NOT PLAY THE PIANO" But the feet monster did not appear.
但是只有腳的妖怪沒有出現
I guess this is done.
克服了
Ack! It's the feet monster!
是只有腳的妖怪啊
What got into Diamond today?
光鑽她今天到底是怎麼了
I'm back.
我回來了
Welcome back, Kita.
妳回來啦 小北
Diamond, what's with the animals?
光鑽 這些動物是怎麼回事
They are here for my special training.
牠們是來協助我做特訓的
Special training?
特…特訓
Ravens and black cats are bad omens.
是啊 烏鴉和黑貓 不是有不吉的意思嗎
I brought them here to break my curse.
所以要用牠們來打破魔咒…
My collection of lanterns!
我的收藏啊
A special training to dispel curses?
打破魔咒的特訓
Yes. It's what I'm doing.
是啊 我是這樣想的
My family curse is very real
里見的魔咒應該是真有其事
and it cannot be dispelled by my strength alone.
光有實力是無法戰勝它的
Therefore, I'll undergo a special training
所以我要進行特訓
so that I will not be fazed when something happens in Kikuka Sho.
好讓我在菊花賞時 無論發生什麼事都不為所動
So that's why you brought a black cat and a raven here.
這樣啊 所以才會把 黑貓和巨嘴鴉帶進房間啊
Just… don't push yourself too far.
但是…妳別太勉強自己了
I'll be fine. You should stop worrying about me, Kita.
沒事的 小北就是愛操心
I'll go out for a jog now.
那我出去跑步了
This late?
這麼晚還要練嗎
Yes. I didn't get enough training this morning.
是啊 今天早上的練習量不夠
I'm off.
我出去了
Take care.
路上小心
7 URBAN LEGENDS OF TRACEN ACADEMY
(特雷森學園七大不可思議 003) (喝下666毫升蜂蜜飲的人) (將會大難臨頭)
11:59PM
(晚間11點59分)
12AM
(深夜12點)
WHAT IS KIKUKA SHO?
(何為菊花賞)
KIKUKA SHO
(菊花賞)
I will overcome every obstacle.
無論是什麼困難我都要跨越
I will win G1 for my family.
然後我要為里見奪下GI
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《賽馬娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
My family…
里見家…
We often hold social or charity events
我們家為了 對賽馬娘比賽文化發展有所貢獻
to promote horse girl racing.
進行了各種協辦以及慈善事業活動
That said,
但是…
the best way to contribute
對比賽文化最大的貢獻
is to present a horse girl who wins G1. But that hasn't happened.
也就是培養出贏得GI賽事的賽馬娘 卻遲遲未能實現
"SPORTS DAY" I am lucky enough to be gifted
(運動會) 我很幸運地擁有跑步的資質
People came to watch me run,
有人會願意來看我奔跑
and they cheered when I got first place.
也有人也因為我奪得第一而高興
It made me proud too.
自小我就會因為這種事開心不已
Naturally, going professional became my dream.
這樣的我 很自然地也擁有了夢想
And like my sisters, I want
也就是跟其他的里見姐姐們一樣
to win G1 for my family.
為里見奪下GI勝利的夢想
However…
然而…
ATHLETES LOUNGE
(準備室)
I did my best…
我已經盡我最大的努力了…
But G1 is beyond my reach.
GI…真的很遙遠呢
Sorry, Diamond.
光鑽 抱歉…
You'll have to carry all our dreams on your shoulders.
將所有的期待都加諸在妳的身上
Whenever I pick up the broken dreams of my retired sisters,
每次我背負起 離開草地的姐姐們的遺憾與心願時
I vow
我都會對自己立下誓言
to win for them too.
我要連大家的份一起獲勝
I will bring a ray of hope to my family.
我為要里見來帶勝利… 帶來希望之光
But…
然而…
So even Diamond can't win in G1.
居然連光鑽也贏不了啊…
She's so promising
她這麼有實力
but she can never get first place.
卻一直跟冠軍失之交臂
The Satono curse is real.
里見魔咒是確實存在的
We can never win G1 no matter how hard we try.
不論再怎麼努力都是贏不下GI的
What's the point of debuting then?
我們出道真的有意義嗎
I have to win.
我必須要贏才行
I need to restore everyone's faith.
我要獲勝 為大家帶來希望才行
I must…
我要…
A special training to dispel curses?
是喔 打破魔咒的特訓啊
She keeps increasing her training hours.
她一直增加她的練習時間
No matter what concerns I raise, she'll just tell me that she's fine.
不論我對她說什麼 她都只會跟我說"她沒事"
But is she truly fine?
但是她真的沒事嗎
Is now the time to worry about others?
現在是擔心別人的時候嗎
She's strong. She'll be fine.
她實力很強 肯定沒事的
But…
可是…
It's normal to be worried for your friend.
擔心朋友是正常的吧
Unlike you, Kitasan cares a lot about her friends.
北部跟妳不一樣 她很關心朋友的
What? I care the most about my friends.
什麼 沒人比我更關心朋友了好不好
-I symbolize friendship. -Find a way to get rid of her bad luck.
-我可是友情賽馬娘耶 -設法讓她別被厄運纏上不就好了嗎
-She needs some nutritious drinks.
-這種時候就要喝營養飲料
-That's right. -Something to remove her bad luck…
-是啊 -原來如此 袪除厄運嗎
Will a charm do?
那就是護身符了吧
Nutritious drinks!
要喝營養飲料
One more lap.
再來一次
You are very motivated.
妳很有衝勁呢
Mc… McQueen?
麥…麥昆
Why are you here?
妳怎麼會在這裡
Can we talk?
要不要來聊聊
How are you feeling?
狀態如何
Very good.
非常好
I have to win the final race
經典三冠的最後一場比賽
of the triple crown classic races.
無論如何我都一定要贏
Kitasan is worried about you.
北部她很擔心妳
Me too.
而且我也很在意
Oh… As usual, she worries about others too much.
真…真是的 小北就是愛瞎操心呢
Is that so?
真是這樣嗎
You are at your limit, aren't you?
妳在勉強自己對吧
"Satono horse girls can't win G1."
"里見的賽馬娘贏不下GI"
Have you heard of this curse?
妳有聽過這個魔咒嗎
Yes.
有
It's just a superstition.
不可能有那種魔咒
Only fools will believe that.
傻子才會去相信那種事
That was what I had been telling myself.
我一直都這樣想
However,
但是…
I can't keep losing.
我不能再輸下去了
I must dispel the curse in Kikuka Sho…
我一定要在這次的菊花賞中 打破里見的魔咒…
Curses are invented by those who benefited from hindsight.
我認為魔咒這種東西 都是後來被人穿鑿附會的
That's not true.
沒有那種事
When I was in Satsuki Sho or Derby, I…
因為皐月賞還有德比的時候我都…
Have you heard of another saying then?
那妳有聽過這種傳言嗎
"Only the strongest horse girl can win Kikuka Sho."
"只有最強賽馬娘才能贏下菊花賞"
Yes, I have heard of that.
我有聽過…
If those legends or myths are true,
如果這些傳言真有如此魔力
it means that a certain special power allows Kitasan and I to win in Kikuka Sho.
那我和北部就只是因為這種魔咒 才有辦法贏下菊花賞對吧
It's thanks to this preternatural gift that we won.
是這種神奇力量引領我們獲得冠軍
That's not true. You and Kita won because you two are very strong.
不是的 小北和麥昆之所以會贏 是因為妳們真的很強
There are no special forces in play or…
才不是因為什麼魔咒…
See? Curses are invented by those
魔咒不過就只是如此罷了
who benefited from hindsight.
全都是人們的穿鑿附會
In spring, you had an unlucky streak.
春季時的里見確實很不走運
But underperforming or horseshoe falling off are normal occurrences in a race.
但是比賽中賽況不佳或是蹄鐵脫落 都是常有的事
Normal occurrences, huh?
常有的事…
Yes.
是啊
It's like when people say that only the strongest horse girl wins.
跟最強賽馬娘贏下菊花賞一樣常見
"She'll win anyway. She makes the race dull".
"因為太強所以一點也不有趣"
Will hearing this from the horse girl who received comments like this
從被人做出這種評價的 菊花賞賽馬娘嘴裡說出來
convince you?
很有說服力吧
But the curse…
可是魔咒…
I know what you're going through.
我懂妳的心情
You're racing for your family.
那種為了家族而戰的心境
You carry the expectations of your family with you.
還有那背負全族期待比賽的壓力
It must be soul-crushing.
一定很痛苦吧
But you didn't run away.
但妳卻沒有逃避
You forge on and do your best even though it's exhausting.
無論有多辛苦都還是注視著前方 奉獻出妳的所有
Not everyone can do that.
這不是任何人都做得到的事
You got third place in Satsuki Sho even though something got in your way.
在決勝時刻被阻擋了跑道 卻還是拿下皐月賞第三名
You got second place in Japanese Derby even though your horseshoe fell off.
以及就算蹄鐵脫落 也以些微之差奪下亞軍的日本德比
In my eyes, you are more resilient than anyone else.
在我的眼裡 妳比任何人都還要強
The hard work you put in,
這些累積至今的努力
the resolution you manifested,
以及堅持下來的信念
they cannot and will not be invalidated by a curse people invented.
全都不是後來被人杜撰的魔咒 所能動搖的
McQueen…
麥昆…
So please, have faith in yourself.
所以妳要對自己有自信一點
You are a very promising horse girl.
妳是很強的賽馬娘
Rest well
要好好休養身體
and be in tip top shape before the race.
再以萬全的狀態來面對比賽
That's all.
只要這樣就夠了
Do you get it now?
妳還不懂嗎
If not, let me give you some advice.
那我就給妳一個特別的建議吧
A hare and a tortoise…
一隻兔子看到一隻烏龜…
Can I ask for a favour?
我可以拜託妳一件事嗎
Yes?
什麼事呢
Please be there in Kikuka Sho.
請妳來看這次菊花賞的比賽
I'll be the first to cross the finish line.
我一定會比所有人更快衝過終點的
Okay. I can't wait to see that.
好 我很期待妳的表現
Thank you.
謝謝妳
I'm back…
我回來了…
You're back, Diamond.
妳回來啦 光鑽
Kita…
小北…
What are those things for?
妳拿這麼多東西是要做什麼
To dispel the curse for you, I bought many lucky charms.
為了讓光鑽打破魔咒 我蒐集了各種幸運小物
Take this.
這個給妳
Thank you.
謝謝妳
Sorry for making you worry.
抱歉讓妳擔心了
I'm fine right now.
我已經沒事了
Thank goodness.
太好了
Here. To celebrate the return of the Diamond I know!
那就為光鑽的復活 乾杯
We have many spectators today at the Kyoto Racecourse this autumn.
好的 在這秋季京都競馬場 聚集了眾多觀眾
This is the final race of the triple crown classic races.
今天是經典三冠賽事的最後一戰
Which horse girl will be crowned today?
這最後的榮耀 會降臨在哪位賽馬娘的身上呢
A track of 3,000 meters long.
3000公尺的草地賽道
18 horse girls.
以18位最大參賽人數來進行比賽
Athletes, please get in position.
好的 各賽馬娘開始就位
Have faith in myself,
要相信自己
the Diamond who runs with the hopes
相信那背負了眾多信念
and the expectations of her family.
為了被託付的心願 而奔跑至今的那個自己
The last horse girl, No. 18, Royal Flannel, is in the horse gate.
最後的18號皇家格紋 也進入了閘門
I am stronger than anyone.
我比任何都還要強
Kikuka Sho
菊花賞
begins now!
開跑了
No. 17, Tip Of The Tongue, is off to a bad start.
17號舌尖現象的起跑晚了一步
-Go! -No. 2, Jakarta Funk, is in the lead.
-衝啊… -領先的是2號雅加達放克
No. 5, Cabin Pilot, overtook her.
5號座艙長閃過了她
They are running as fast as they can.
兩人雙雙衝了出去
The highly-anticipated Satono Diamond is behind them five to six horse lengths.
備受矚目的里見光鑽 就在後面5至6個馬身的位置
They say only the strongest horse girl can win in the final race
相傳在經典三冠賽中的 最後一場賽事 菊花賞
of the triple crown classic races.
只有最強的賽馬娘能夠勝出
Do you know why?
你知道這是為什麼嗎
It's because…
因為這是場…
You already explained it.
你之前都說過了
The horse girls are heading to the first stretch now.
好的 各賽馬娘 進入了最初的非終點直線
Go!
衝啊…
59.9 seconds for the first lap.
最初的1000公尺成績為59秒9
After receiving applause from the spectators, they head into the first bend.
衝過了觀眾席 接受了觀眾的掌聲後進入第一彎道
All horse girls shuffled into a line.
所有選手化為長條隊列
A line of 20 horse lengths
長達20馬身的隊列進入了第一彎道
-Go! -ushers into the first bend.
-衝啊… -長達20馬身的隊列進入了第一彎道
Diamond.
光鑽…
Bring hope to the horse girls in our family.
讓里見家的賽馬娘們看見希望吧
You can do this, Diamond.
妳一定可以的 光鑽小姐
800 meters left. We're now at the third bend.
剩下800公尺 進入第三彎道
No. 5, Cabin Pilot, is still in the lead.
現在是5號座艙長一馬當先
I carry
我正背負著…
the regret, the wishes, and the faith
里見家賽馬娘們的遺憾和心願
of my family.
還有她們的信念
I will bring them
我要獻給他們
the light of glory
勝利的光輝
and the ray of hope.
還有希望的光芒
I will realize my dream
我要現實我的夢想
and my family's goal.
達成里見的夙願
I will be stronger and faster
我比任何人都還要強
than anyone!
還要快
Diamond!
光鑽
No. 3, Satono Diamond speeds up.
好的 3號里見光鑽衝了上來
No. 6, Divinity, also picks up her pace.
6號神力也加快了速度
Both of them head to the final stretch.
兩人雙雙進入了直線
No. 5, Cabin Pilot, is still two horse lengths ahead.
領先在前的5號座艙長 則在她們兩個馬身的前方
Go!
衝啊…
We're at the final stretch. Everyone is giving their all.
來到了最終直線 所有選手進入最後衝刺
They now arrive at the spectator rows, where crowds are cheering loudly for them.
衝向了歡聲雷動的觀眾席前
Go!
衝啊…
No. 3, Satono Diamond, is on the flank.
外側是3號里見光鑽
Two horse lengths behind her is No. 6, Divinity.
兩個馬身的後方是6號神力
Behind them, Original Light
而在後方的原初閃亮也追了上來
-Diamond. -accelerates too.
-光鑽 -而在後方的原初閃亮也追了上來
She's here!
衝出來了
No. 3, Satono Diamond, overtakes everyone.
3號里見光鑽衝出重圍
No. 13, Jewel Spinel, is on the inside line.
內側是13號珠寶尖晶
On the flank, No. 11, Rainbow Thread, is fighting for 2nd place with Divinity.
外側則是11號七色線 與2號神力在爭奪第二名
Satono Diamond is 100 meters away from achieving her family's dream!
里見光鑽 距離里見家的夙願只剩下100公尺
Satono Diamond maintains her lead
里見光鑽以壓倒性的優勢
and crosses the finishing line!
衝過終點
What an awe-inspiring final sprint!
一口氣跑完直線 驚人的尾段衝刺
Satono Diamond, well done!
好強 妳太強了 里見光鑽
No. 3, Satono Diamond, got first place!
3號里見光鑽 獲得了壓倒性的勝利
Competing for second place
爭奪第二名的
are No. 11, Original Light, on the flank,
是外側的第11號原初閃亮
-Diamond! -are No. 11, Original Light, on the flank,
-光鑽 -是外側的第11號原初閃亮
-No. 13, Jewel Spinel, from inside,
-和內側的13號珠寶尖晶
and No. 6, Divinity, who was squeezed in between them.
以及在她們中間的6號神力 三位選手
Hooray!
太好了…